Hello. Good morning. Am I live? Looks
like I am alive. Alive and kicking.
Hello there. Okay. So, let's uh show you
the screen. So, we going going to do
some coding. This is the usual talk
show. Uh I'm an old programmer and uh uh
you know unusual character and I code
and stuff. I'm known for Emacs. Good
morning, GK4K.
Okay, we're going to have some red wine.
This is uh 150 ml of red wine to soothe
my soul. Red wine.
And we're going to code Emacs. Emacs and
JavaScript. Okay. So, let's adjust this
uh so it my microphone so it doesn't hit
the red bar. Okay. So, the keyboard is
Ultimate Hacking Keyboard 2. Check out
my YouTube video. You will see my
reviews. Ultimate hacking keyboard.
Okay. So, let me adjust the microphone
so it doesn't go clip.
Rewind. Uh, wait. Can you see what
screen do you see? Yeah. So, you see my
uh So, let's see. Uh,
stop this. Okay. Stop that and put it
down. So, now you are looking at my
screen. That's correct. Close that.
Have some drink. Close that. Showing
browser. So you're looking at today's
talk show. What we going to do? I
haven't had a drink yet. Let me sip.
So busy talking. Okay. So we we we're
going to do um
we're going to code emacr command to
minify
a javascript code by calling deno. Okay,
I'm going to that's what I need to do.
So I'm going to show you and here you
are looking at AI answers. So AI helped
me how do you uh minify
uh JavaScript or TypeScript JavaScript
mostly
bundle and minify you know that's very
complicated JavaScript technology in the
past 15 years
so we're going to write a EMAC command
coding emac bisp to you know so I press
a key it'll automatically
so let me show you okay so let's uh
start to So let's see unic code. So let
me show you some of my unic code project
that has heavy typescript or javascript.
So unic code uh unic code search. So you
can see this page. Let me magnify the
page. So you can see type like smile sm
i l. You see as you type the result
shows. So all these characters are
unicode characters whose name contains
the word smil.
So this is uh of course so that is
written uh in javascript in fact
typescript. So let's go to see the code
uh unic code. So, so you go to uh wait
well actually uh so you go unic code
search uh unic code um well you know you
can go to
uh search so you can see here is the
several files
uh let's highlight the word search so
you can see better so there are several
files containing whose name contains the
word search the unic code search page
you are looking at is is actually okay.
So I moved uh page move to unic code
index. Okay. So it actually went to
index
uh AI index blog index computer
programming index unic code index
semantic index syntax pass index. Oh god
where did it go? Unicode art index.
Jesus. So this is page. This page is the
unic code search. Okay. Uh and you know
so on this page you search for.js
you can see. So that's the unic code
search uh code. So this is TS means it's
JavaScript. I mean TypeScript you can
see that TS and
so you see so and and it compile to
JavaScript. So this is JavaScript. Open
it. So it compiles they look very nice.
I want to minify it. So how do you do
it? You can do it in demo. So um let's
split the window drop to directory. So
drop to directory. So you can see and uh
so watch. Okay. So uh copy the file path
and new open a new buffer paste it. So
that's a file name. So you want do
uh bundle and minifi something like
that. Okay. So that's how you do it in
by command line. By the way, this is
very interesting uh Unico character. You
got this [laughter]
lower right quadrant smiling face. Can
you see? Uh okay. So can you can you
like see um you know this these two? Oh
god, I missed I should have that. Um
okay, digression. I need to add that.
Okay, actually I need to add that. But
hold on a second. So we have multiple
things going on. So let's go to Unicode
blog and I want to add that those
characters. Okay, it doesn't show in
here but never ne never the less
I didn't know there are these two
characters I missed them. You see
because um because I was collecting
those characters and I can show you some
of it. Okay. Uh we have some
digressions. We let's log the entry. So
hold on a second. So,
so we got so many things going on. Okay.
So, let's go to Yeah, let's pop out the
chat so I can see you guys. Pop out
chat. So, if you are here, say hi. Okay,
now put that back. Tiny sip.
Okay, so let's um Well, we're going to
finish this
K4K. Who are you? Where you from?
Okay. So, so Unicode. So, let me show
you Unicode. Very interesting
characters. You got these funky
characters. Okay. Uh Microsoft Windows
11 emoji gun trans.
It's a article you can read. Okay.
Search for.info
unicode blog. Okay. Then you got
repurposed unicode characters. That's a
essay incomplete. I haven't finished.
Basically, it means some unic code
characters they for example this
character is called hot beverage. One of
the earliest Unicode characters
beginning in um uh 200
this character began in 201
10. Uh when did Unicode emoji begin? I
forgot. Wait, I I must remember. Um when
did Unicode emoji begin? That must
begin.
I forgot. Uh, is it 2010?
So, we can ask AI Glock, help us or we
can uh
control J to start a new conversation.
Wait, Ctrl J. Yeah, start a new
conversation.
uh and or we can go to uh
diet. Okay. So I mean uh let me let so
we we got multiple things going on.
Okay. So let me uh
we are branching out. So let me uh get a
hold of myself. So let's so we know what
we're talking about. So okay. So let
let's go to the talk show.
Uh let's go to the talk show. Okay. So
let's do so that's today's talk show.
Let's start to take notes. Okay. So,
first of all, we need to do this minifi
but uh
talk about this unic code funky chart
and we want to do and we want to uh uh
this is uni code search. Oh yeah.
Minifi. Okay. So demonstrate minifi
demo deno minify.
Okay.
And so that and we want to now we want
to know when did unic code emoji begin.
We can know that by multiple ways. Okay.
We can know by note that by unic code
version which is one of my articles. So
you can go here uh unic code repurposed
unic code characters unic code search
unic code block and go all the way down
go to the unic code um
miscellaneous. Okay. So there is a
section on unic code versions. So there
so unic code six emoticons.
So Unilico's
begin emoji begin in 2010. [snorts]
Unico version 6 is released in 2010
October. This version adds 2,88
characters. One thing interesting is
that it adds about 68
emoticons.
You know it is, you know, it today it's
called emo emoji. Okay. But back then it
wasn't so clear. So we can ask AI
when did Uniode start to have emoji?
What year?
2010, that's when Unicode officially
added emoji in version 6.0, released in
October. Before that, they existed
mainly on Japanese phones, but 2010 is
when they became a standard part of
Unicode.
>> Thank you, Eve. You are lovely.
Thank you. That's so sweet of you to
say.
>> 2010. You see, I have documented. So
now, let's copy that and go to my talk
page. Go to talk show. Today's talk
show.
Paste the link. Linkify it. Make a list
so that we document what we the things
we have talked about. Okay. When did
unic code emoji begin? And here back to
the guac AI and screenshot it make a
copy of the record of the fact of the
year 2026
we have this conversation and you know
after 10 years it would become
interesting because it would show that
it's a piece of history you know oh 10
years ago when AI began it looks like
that you know imagine what will happen
after 10 Yes,
hopefully we still exist. Okay. Anyway,
so we got a record of it and
press press fantastic and advanced emacs
command which automatically move certain
files into the current directory. So you
can see so this uh copy the file name of
the current file and rename that link by
pasting what we just copied talk show
episode 8001
and let's just say this is um emoji
uh
AI guac emoji okay so we have renamed
the file so you can see it automatically
renamed it on the file on the disk as
well and as well made the link. So now
copy the file I mean so yeah cop grab
the all the URLs in this block and now
paste it relink it. So we rel it. Now
you see the reason it's different
because we changed the name. So when you
relink the name it automatically
generate this figure caption based on
the file name. Okay.
But whereas before you see even though
we renamed the file but we did not
regenerate the figure caption. So that's
why I'm redoing it. So now this part
this these two are exactly
the same file name. So we don't need
this block anymore. Delete it. Now we
can just show in browser. Press a key.
Show in browser. And we can see a
screenshot. You see? Fantastic. Go back
to Emacs. Okay. That's one task done. We
No. No. No, when so uh unic code gen uh
unic code emoji began in the year of our
lord 2010. Okay. Emoji which is a kind
of big deal. Okay. Because historically
from linguistics point of view, history
point of view uh emoji is part of the
English
uh part of like the writing system which
became
uh widely spread among all English
speakers as well as the but mostly
English speakers because they became
part of the re writing system of of the
English language like alphabets a A to Z
along with punctuation. So in year 2010,
human animals of the English speaking
part began to have this emoji thing as
part of the everyday life. Okay. So
that's you know that's you know so
happens by the way. So we are talking
about that character. So let's go back.
So let's um
Unicode blog copy the link close and uh
let's uh hold on a second. So let's uh
link linkify unic code blog and so we
have a record of what we talked about.
So unic code blog. So I was going to
show you. So repurpose unic code
characters. I was talking about this
this article is
in the first draft has not been written
yet but I was talking about repurposed
unicore characters meaning that so in so
in 2010 we have this hot beverage
character. Okay. But later on, Unicode
adds uh you know a full set of
characters for food like like pizza
drink red wine uh cocktail glass saki
uh tumbler glass teacup without handle
teapot bubble tea. That's a bubble. You
know by the way you know what bubble
means? Bble means big tits.
So original. You see this is fun. Uh let
me explain. Okay. So today if you are
young you might know there's a bubble
you know there's a drink called bubble
tea. You may find it like in San
Francisco like western cities where they
typically where there are Chinese Asian
people. Okay. But it's very fairly
popular in tech industry like like silic
silicon valley San Francisco uh and
probably New York. Okay. So if you are
around those areas, you know, there's
this bubble tea sold by I I don't think
Starbucks has it, but it's like similar
shops of Starbucks, you know, for where
young people go to have coffee. So you
got this bubble tea. Now the bubble tea
original name, it began in 19 uh if I
remember around 1997, okay, like there,
okay, in Taiwan or Hong Kong. Okay. So,
but but it became popular I mean even in
USA so around 1997
in Taiwan and Hong Kong it must began
earlier. Okay. Uh
so and and so you know so the original
Chinese name is called
which which if you translate in English
it means like
wavy giant milk tea. So what does the
wavy giant mean? It actually it's a slan
for huge tits. Okay, like women's
breast, huge tits,
but the slant is like wavy giant. Okay,
so it's saying, you know, it's saying,
what does it mean? It's literally wavy
giant milk tea. So, what do you mean
wavy giant? Well, that means huge tits
milk tea. Okay, so that's the origin.
So, but today in English is just known
as bubble tea because bubble kind of
sounds similar to the ba. Okay. So, we
can actually ask AI to explain. Okay.
Explain the origin of bubble milk tea.
It started in Taiwan in the 1980s. Two
shops claim credit. Hanland Tea Room in
Thailand says they invented it in 1986
by adding white tapioca pearls to milk
tea. While Chunu Tang in Taiong credits
an employee who mixed tapioca balls into
iced milk tea around 1987 or 1988. The
drink quickly caught on and spread from
there.
>> How do they call it in Chinese?
It's called jenju nicha, pronounced
jenju na, literally pearl milk tea. In
Taiwan, you'll also hear people just say
boba na, boba milk tea.
>> So, can you explain the boba milk tea?
Boba milk tea is just another name for
bubble tea or pearl milk tea. It's a
sweet Taiwanese drink from the 1980s
made with milk tea and chewy tapioca
pearls at the bottom. Boba comes from
the Chinese word borba, slang for big
breasts, a cheeky reference to the
round, bouncy pearls. In Taiwan, it's
mostly called janju na, but boba caught
on big in the US. Want the recipe or how
to make the pearls yourself?
Thank you. I love the name Giant Tits
Milk Tea.
>> You're welcome. The name's pretty
cheeky, isn't it?
[laughter]
>> But in America, the white people, you
know, under Christianity, they they they
you know, they, you know, they they have
to think twice when they say things like
that, you know, like giant tits or the
wavy, you know, the huge wave milk tea.
uh you know like ba. So what it mean
literally it means bba means like wavy
and ba means like um like a bully. Okay.
Like you know like a school bully you
know like wavy bully because it's huge.
Okay.
So that's the origin of this bubba milk
tea. Okay. You know so after now by now
40 years it came what is it 80? Yeah. 40
years it came to unic code known as
bubble bubble tea. Okay.
So anyway, so around 2000 uh so when did
the unic code food emoji came about? Um
so we can ask AI again. So food emoji
that came about like um I don't remember
but we can look up at my records. Okay.
Uh unic code. So unic code.
So let's copy that because we talked
about that. God, we going nowhere
anytime. So we talking about the unic
code origin of the unic code emoji.
Okay. Then you go down then you'll find
the unic code versions. So when did they
started to add food? I don't remember
but um but let's see.
They started to add lots of food around
is it 2016 or 2017 or 18? That's my
guess. Let's check. Okay. 2014, 15, 16,
17, 18, 19. I would say 2016 to 2018.
They added lots of the Unicode food
emoji.
Okay. So, CS use Unicode 7 2014. very
interesting and beautiful characters.
Leaf ornaments, vine leaf ornaments.
Okay, most people don't know like you
guys don't know. Okay, so you know
that's why you are watching my talk
show. I hope it's interesting to you. If
you are here, say hi. Okay, so now
Unicode 8 2015. So what did they add in
Unicode 8? Okay, they started the skin
colors. They began the social justice
warrior skin colors and and there
[laughter] from there on it's kind of
downhill. Okay. And and there they begin
to have food like they demand well if
you have rice well we need cheese. We
need hot dog, we need taco to represent
Mexicans. We need burrito. Okay. And
then we need bottle with popping cork.
Okay. So then 2000 and Unicode 9 2016
we began we started to more food I think
somewhere. Okay. Shrimp, octopus,
shrimp and squid. Yeah. Food. Kiwi,
avocado, potato, carrot, cucumber,
peanuts, croissant
baguette.
Okay. Pancakes, you know, and bacon. Oh,
lovely bacon. delicious stuffed
flatbread and eggs and you know so you
see so basically beginning in 200 um
in 2015
and
2018 uh uh uh 15 2015 and 2016.
Okay. and
Unicode 10 2017. Let's see. Did they
have also a lot of food? I believe so.
Okay. So, 2017 17 more food. Of course.
Now, you need uh we demand cut up meat.
We demand a representation, a pictorial
representation of meat,
the classic white man's food and semi
white man's food and coconut. Okay. We
demand broccoli. Okay.
This is from the uh what they call uh
the [laughter]
you know the the the the well let's not
be um anyway broccoli okay like you need
to be healthy right by the way I love
broccoli well in part because I got you
know I was told broccoli is very healthy
for you make you live forever okay boil
with spoon and canned food and oh
dumplings you need to you have uh you
need to Asian Chinese representation.
Chinese fortune cookies and pie. Oh, the
pie. The western apple pie. New York.
New York pretzels. New York. New York
cup withdraw. So you you need chopsticks
of course and you need take out box.
Okay. So you see I was correct. So
around 2014 to 2018,
we added a whole bunch of this unic code
food emoji. Okay, so where did it go? So
let's uh go it go to it food. Okay, so
like there's lots of
Okay, so what I'm saying originally now
let's go back to uh what we were saying.
So we were saying that uh next next we
were saying that okay so we were saying
showing browser. So we were saying uni
code block we were saying that
repurposed unic code characters. So the
coffee the hot beverage emoji began in
2010.
Then after that in starting from 2014 to
uh 18 you know they added whole set of
like 30 50
emoji characters for food and among them
lots of for drinks. Okay. But now
there's a issue. Okay. You see there you
know even among all the food emojis
there's none that actually says coffee.
the most popular drink among the white
men. You know, you got m you got beer,
you got red wine, you got cocktail, you
got sakai, saki, Japanese drink, you got
tumbler glass for whiskey and stuff. You
got teacup, you got teapot, you got
bubble milk tea, you got made from
Brazilians and uh Guatemala and Mexico
and the uh
you know the South America drink like uh
their coffee, you know, and you got milk
and you got a cup of withdraw and you
got the kids beverage box, but there's
none that actually named coffee. Why?
Because when this character when there
was only one hot beverage character,
people use it as coffee as a symbol for
coffee. Okay? So even the name is
technically just hot beverage. It
doesn't say coffee. It could be just hot
water.
However, there's none other. So people
use this symbol, you know, because it's
what's a hot beverage? Well, coffee. So
this symbol is used for coffee even
though the name doesn't say it.
But then so then people started to add
all kind of beverages but it's missing
coffee. Why? Well so why didn't they add
coffee? Why why why don't you know we
have all these drinks? Why don't we have
one character for coffee in Unicode?
Well that's because this hot beverage
you know is used for to stand for
coffee. So, so that's why so you you so
you kind of got this weird situation.
You see that's my point. You got this
weird situation. You know, you got this
beverages for all kind of beverages, but
you you missing the most popular coffee.
Well, that's because
we use the hot beverage. The hot
beverage character became coffee
essentially. Okay. So that's a kind of
very uh interesting phenomenon in
Unicode. Okay, repurposed Unicode
characters. Okay, the hot beverage a
generic
emoji became coffee and then but you
miss coffee. You know, you miss you miss
explicit coffee emoji. Okay, that's one
example. There's others. Okay. So the
other examples are for example the um
this uh heavy black heart heavy um and
and end black heart. Basically you don't
have a red heart. Okay. So let me
explain this one. Uh so I haven't fully
written this out yet but but but
basically you got hearts of all colors.
You got orange hot, pink heart, yellow
heart, green heart, light blue heart,
blue heart, purple heart. You got white
heart, you got gray heart, you got brown
hot heart, you got black heart. But the
most popular color for heart is red hot.
But you don't have it. Instead you have
heavy black heart, you have white hot
sweet, you have black heart sweet. You
don't have a unic character that's named
red hot. Okay, so it's a very
interesting phenomenon. Okay, so I'm
writing this essay titled repurposed
unic code characters. Okay, I explained
that. Okay, so that's a digression.
That's a kind of digression.
Oh god, we are digressing. We digressed
over. So we [laughter]
we were going to do the unic code the
the the types squid deno bundle minifi.
Okay. So is it funny? Is it is it good
for you guys?
Hi. I want to sip some boba milk tea. A
vegetarian emoji. Oh Jesus. My red
wine is good. Now I feel like I need to
pour some more.
You know, we bought actually we
bought white wine today. Actually, maybe
I should try white wine. B b b b b b b b
b b b b b b b b b b b b bubbling
sparkling wine. So, you see I'm trying
uh so in the recent month I've been
trying to drink uh alcohol kind of the
white man's obsession.
You know, you got vodka, you got all
kind of
uh but uh anyway. Uh okay. So we digress
so much. Are we going to So what we
going to So I was going to talk about
Yeah. So I was going to I was showing
you about the
Unicode search application. You see uh
we were demo the Unicode search.
Fantastic. Okay. So just on.info search
it you'll find it. Unicore search. Okay.
Type any character you'll find
immediately.
And yeah, so we I was gonna tell you
about these fun funky characters. Okay.
Uh now what what you want to know about
that? You back to go back to the unicode
block and let me show you. Okay. So let
me just show you that part. Um
that part would be uh
here. Unicode funky weird characters.
You see one of them is this. [laughter]
Can you guys see? Can you Can you guys
see this? Let me magnify. Okay. Like ma
magnify gazillion.
You see this character? This is upper
left quadrant face with open eyes. You
see this is upper right quadrant face
with open eyes. You see this upper left
quadrant face with closed eyes.
[laughter]
Funny, but I didn't realize. So, we
discovered a new one today. So, um yeah.
So, today's talk show we I just by
chance
uh we discover uh we discovered a new
one which we wrote it down here. Okay.
So, go back to Emacs. Search for fun. So
there. So let me let's add that back to
that page. So go back here,
press a key to copy the URL and switch
to the last app. Press it. Fantastic
keyboard magic because the Kasar system
and keyboard ultimate hacking keyboard.
Okay.
Paste it there. Linkify. Make a list.
Delete the URL there. Okay. Now copy
these two characters. Paste it back. Now
go to this page. Open it. Go down. We
need to add uh we need to add. Go down.
Go down. Go down. Okay. Now paste those.
Make them one line per character. Do it.
Now we need to annotate. Okay. So press
press. Magic. And this one. Press press
press press. So we expand a single
character into the into a span tag with
complete information about that
character. For example, this character
is unic code
1 CCAB. The unic code um code point okay
one CCAB in hexadimal and the name of
the character is lower right quadrant
smiling face. Okay. Now it doesn't show
in Emacs because
the font I I have doesn't have it.
Actually it should but you know because
this because there's it's not showing
because there's a lot of technical
quirks. Okay. Now make it a paragraph.
Okay. You see now showing browser. So
now you go down.
So you you see we added this funky
thing. Very funny. Okay. So that's unic
code. So now you can actually you can
search for quadrant and uh you see you
if you search for quadrant face you
might find others. So let's try it.
Okay. And also we need to update today's
date. Okay. So
you see so today's date you see uh
there. So press press press
automatically update show in browser.
There it's updated to today's date. Now
let's go to unic code miscellaneous
index and go to unic code search and
paste quadron phase. So you got so oh so
here is the complete list. Copy it. So
let's add the complete list. Okay.
Uh okay. So we digress so much. So
anyway, so yeah. So I suppose this uh go
back here. So you got the very funky.
Okay. So
each two of them makes a pair. Okay. So
uh that's a pair. Uh but anyway, so you
need press press. Okay. So record a
keyboard macro. This is emac magic.
Okay. Now move here.
Press press. That's HTML mode magic.
Okay. Stop the keyboard marker and go
here. Select all these lines. Press
press press. Apply them the marker to
all the lines. Done. Now every two
characters make a unit. Okay. So now
make uh make it larger. Every two
characters make a unit. Okay. What is
this? Yeah. So every two car characters,
you know, we add a buu. Okay.
Okay. BU is a bullet. We add a bullet
there. Okay. We add a bullet. Okay.
Okay. That's it. Now make it a
paragraph. Now ehr make a line break and
copy the line break and go to the top.
Paste the line break showing browser.
So now scroll down.
Fantastic. We got the complete list. Can
you see? Fantastic. Now, we don't need
this uh the one at the bottom. Okay.
Now, back to Emacs. So, now this we
don't need. Uh wait, we need this. Uh
but here we don't need. Okay. Uh delete
that. Delete that. And delete that.
Showing browser.
Fantastic. We did it.
So, this is uh happen stance. We
digressed and we happen to work on this.
Very interesting. Okay.
Ah Jesus. I need to actually I need some
uh get some more drink. Vegetarian
emoji. So nobody's here. Nobody is like
watching my show I guess. Okay. I guess
nobody's watching the show. Okay. So
showing browser that's the page is done.
Close. Back here. Close. Okay. Uh
showing browser. So we did talk about
the unic code characters. So, one thing
at a time. Okay. So, we talked about the
Unicode blog, my Unicode blog. And we
talked about the funky characters. Okay.
Very funky Unicode characters. Okay.
Then we talked about when did emoji
begin? Okay. Begin 2010. And we also
asked as ask AI about it. Very
interesting. And we talked about
repurposed unicode characters.
Why we do not have a emoji named coffee?
That is why. Okay, we talked about that.
Okay, now get back to So now we need to
now we go back to this minifi. So where
are we talking about unic code? Because
I was trying to demonstrate a JavaScript
application that is my uh application
here. Okay. So copy the file path. um uh
paste it here. So this is a page for
unic code search for the smidey. Okay.
So okay now go back now open this page.
Uh yeah so open open this JavaScript. So
here you are looking at the source code.
You are looking at the typescript. Go to
the directory. So now here is the
JavaScript. Now you want to minify this
code. How do you do that?
Uh, so we are going to do so I Okay, so
we're going to do this quickly. Okay, I
need to focus finish this job. Write a
emac this code to minify JavaScript.
Okay, so how do you minify? So there is
the AI help. AI says do this deno bundle
uh dash minify. So
uh
so okay so that is the code. So split
the screen. New buffer paste deno bundle
d-minify
and the file name. The file name is
that. Okay. So the file name is that
uh oh wait
ts can can so it will compile and bundle
at the same time I think. So let's say
this let's say output is um
what
so how does this work let's say that
okay so you call this command deno
bundle minify
the main code and wait
uh it's going to create one single file.
Okay. So, but I don't want
actually I don't want it to create a
single file because this file reads a um
it this file reads a you know data file
the unic code characters data.
So, but so this is this file does not
load any libraries. So, I believe that
will work. So, let's try it. Okay. So
run this command. Copy it. I'll start a
shell. Paste it. Run it. Okay. So it
says unexpected
argument minify found. What?
What the you talking about? So So
let's start powershell. Okay. Let's
start powershell of the current
directory. So I just press two keys.
That's open in terminal. Okay. That's
kasa emac leis magic. It will open
a shell
of the current buffer directory.
Does not matter you are on windows on
mac or linux it will open the
appropriate shell. Okay for example on
windows it's powershell on the mac it's
z shell on windows on linux it's bash.
Okay. So all you have to do for example
press press press press press press
press press press press you see
fantastic and beautiful power of cas
emac system you don't find efficiency
like that in anywhere in in whatever the
programmers at Google or I created
Python or whatever I created you know
JavaScript not mpm whatever those people
magnifying okay so most sufficient
remember flag keys. So if you are Emacs
user, you need to be Emacs user to enjoy
all these U and you need to pay me
actually to get flag
HTML mode and stuff.
Okay, so what we doing? So we got so
then uh Denos got a problem. Uh so Deno
says unexpected argument minify found
what
uh Deno so did does that mean AI
actually gave the wrong uh Okay so
Deno
help
bundle. Okay let's see what the is
Deno doing.
Deno bundle options. Uh
oh. Deno bundle was removed in Deno2.
What the
So, [laughter]
so basically the idiotic AI is creating
is you know giving us a error is meeting
misleading us. Okay. How to mean how to
minify with deno? Okay. So Deno wait
bundle. Okay. So but deno bundle was
removed in version deno2.
Uh so uh okay so we got misled by AI. So
deno bundle options. Uh
uh well let's ask AI. Okay.
In JavaScript is Deno bundle removed in
Deno version two.
Yes, Deno bundle was removed in Deno 2.0
which launched in late 2024. It came
back in version 2.4 in July 2025 now
powered by ESB build under the hood. So
in current demo versions like 2.9, the
command is available again.
>> Oh, it's available again. So what what
version do am I using? Deno v 2.3.
I need to update my deno.
That means we can't write this today. So
you see, I need to upgrade my deno. Oh
god.
Jesus
Jesus gcm deno okay let's see what where
is my deno my deno is user deno being
denoex executable so [sighs]
okay so you need to upgrade deno
annoying
so my demo is in user bin that means
wait uh where is my deno u
deno bin denoexe so
you see the Way you upgrade demo depends
on how you installed it in the first
place. There are many ways. You can
install it via the Windows uh you know
the
app manager or you can install it by
download manually yourself. Uh so there
are many or you can install it by
chocolate you know the windows package
manager or the there's also win like win
install you know the official windows
manager or you can install it via
windows store you know the Microsoft
software store.
So the way how you upgrade you know
update the version of Deno depends on
how you install that in the first place.
So very fairly uh complex. Okay. I don't
remember how I installed it because I
like each time and for every application
I like
you know I don't re I I don't usually so
I almost never install it for Microsoft
store because that's that's the worst
Uh sometimes I install via chocolate but
at one time I decided I'm not going to
install anything from this middle man
like you know Windows chocolate. Window
chocolate is is a com command line
utility that lets you install any any
basically almost all Unix software or
Windows software. You just type install
something similar to on the Mac. It's
like similar to Mac's brew, you know,
brew install something, you know. So,
it's very convenient, super convenient.
So, on Windows, you have chocolate. Uh,
you know, so if you guys don't know what
I'm talking about, so on Windows, you
have the Windows chocolate.
C H O
L A
uh, you know, C H O L A T E. What? C O
C. Okay. Chocolate. Okay. C H O C Cha uh
ch
chocolate chocolate package manager.
Okay. So, Windows chocolate package man
package manager. Okay. Here's the
article.
And there is a nougat. There's Windows
package manager. So, you know, it's a
bit there are many different options.
Okay. So anyway, sometimes I use cho
choco, but at one time I decided I'm
going to not going to rely on choco
because I want to manually manage
everything. I don't want anything just
magically go to my computer. I want to
control it and I know exactly where gets
installed where. I know every file in my
system. Okay. So So I was going to in
uninstall choco but I it didn't happen.
Okay. So I I still have Choco. So for
example, you can GCM
CH O. So you can see Choco is installed
there.
Uh wait uh application
uh where is Choco application choco
what?
Uh wait. So let me do again
GCM choco. Yeah. So program data
chocolate bin choco. Okay.
So anyway, so but my demo is in casard.
Deno bin. So I need to upgrade it. Okay.
So nobody's watching I think. So um
oh god I need to update deno.
Deno. So in a demo um
uh that's interesting thing we
discovered close that
uh so you can run this command close
that
so you can go to s
uh not
deno
there.
So you got the deno bing.
Okay. My wife is calling me to eat.
Coming. Coming 10 minutes.
My wife is calling me to eat. Uh, very
nice. So, but Deno is the
I need to install Deno. So, let's
go to download directory.
I thought I think I downloaded what
Canadian call syntax for all semantics.
a meta foundational framework beyond the
un valent foundation. Oh, okay. That's
actually that's a mathematician's paper.
Uh but I wanted to um
find what what am I doing?
Uh did I download demo? I think I did,
but I think I also deleted. Okay. So
uh god you need to download deno okay
deno uh version 24 okay so enable
javascript so google knows what you are
what you are doing and uh download deno
windows okay uh deno 2.9
oh it's advanced
okay so did we enable JavaScript
okay [snorts] so click on that why is it
nothing happens.
Okay. So then what
is it downloading? What the is
going on? So make sure now Deno
Deno version 2.3
that's a bit few years old. God, this is
very annoying. All this uh you know and
it's not downloading. Why is it not
downloading? Uh
IRM.
Oh, it just tell you to run this
command.
Know. Oh god. So you see,
okay, so
I got to be careful because now I'm
doing work that will affect my computer.
It's not just a talk show because so new
buffer paste it. So IRM stand for um
uh that is um
help alias. Okay.
Uh [groaning]
GCM
uh actually help
stand for invoke rest method
sends an HTTP or HTTPS request to a
restful web servers rest my ass
anyway that's part of PowerShell okay so
you basically so you getting and IEX
means invoke the script script. Okay,
help exhale stuff in invoke expression.
Okay, so basically you are basically you
are this is like curl. Okay, the Unix
idiots curl or we get that's the
powershell equivalent. Okay. I am. So
you are downloading that script then you
are um then you are like executed.
This is the best way to get virus onto
your computer. You know you like for the
zoomers for the zoomer The
zoomers beginning this began about like
15 years ago. Oh by the way just run
this command. Just copy and paste into
your shell. Okay. the Unix.
the Unix but also but the late
Malay genen. It began with the late
Malay genen with this kind of thing. And
then then of course the zoomers the
zoomers don't know nothing. They grew up
with this never never seen anything
before.
So this so this thing copy. Okay. So
so well I'm not going to run it. I I
have to know what the is going on.
So, open that script. Let's see.
Inspect.
Okay. Obviously, then Okay. Well, it's
going to tell you it's downloading that
script. Okay. Let's download it.
Uh so, install.ps1. It's downloading a
PowerShell script.
Okay. So, let's go to download
directory.
Uh, search for PS1. There, there it is.
The shell script. Okay. The PowerShell
script.
Copyright 2018 to 2020. The Deno
authors. All right. Reserved MIT license
to do everyone. Keep this script simple
and easy easily audit auditable.
them. You see beginning with the
late Melen Jen and Zumas, they have this
word audit. Okay. like meaning like
someone have to inspect your program you
know they call it audit
and so why do I hate it like what's the
problem well the the the issue with lots
of these jargon is that you know instead
of just saying review or check the code
something simple everyone understand
this basically deep state kind of
they begin with you know they
like the like elite jogger academic
mumbo jumbo So audit. So instead of just
saying inspect, review, you know, check
for code quality, check for viruses,
instead of the simple words, everyone
can understand universal, they they they
they in, you know, they have this they
introduce this academic mumbo jumbo like
audit code audit o and and here you have
easily auditable. Okay. [laughter]
So anyway, so they are saying, you know,
keep this short, keep this script short
so that people can actually inspect it,
watch it, you know, check it and see if
it contains virus or something like
that. Okay,
so this script what what am I doing to
my computer? So this script will check
for version. So error action preference.
So this is PowerShell code. Okay, I'm
not going to run until I actually look
at the code. Okay, deno install. Deno
install. So it's what got uh so deno
zip. So what you doing?
Uh so you get this script and you
execute this script. So I'm going to
execute this script and uh and you are
setting a variable
an environment variable and you set a
bin directory environment variable.
Okay, a variable. And then you bin the
deno execute. Okay. Locations you set
location then you set the target. Okay.
Then version if version something curl
it is calling curl which is a Unix
program that download files from the
web. But Microsoft Windows bundled curl.
Okay. Since like Windows 11 or or uh or
sometimes in Windows 10. So you are
calling curl to download uh SSL revoke
best effort.
So you are downloading this um text
file. I suppose that's a text file. Open
that
[laughter]
text file version two latest release
text version 2.91. Okay then. Okay then
you are downloading. So then you Okay.
So this is the multi-layer
script. This script you execute but it's
actually executing another you're going
to you know so you're going to get this
another URL you're going to fetch it.
Okay then
temp directory odd move uh whatever then
then you call curl again get funny you
see funny because over here they are
calling IRM which is the powershell's
way of curl but in the actual code here
they are just calling curl
oh god then they are going to install
deno so do they have viruses I think I
can run this code okay was inst So
successfully run den help to get started
stuck. Okay. So okay so it's telling me
to run the code.
Okay. Now I seen the code. I can trust
it. I can run. Okay.
So okay I got to go. Okay. Because my
you know the deno is ready.
H the deno. Okay. So where is the
um Oh yeah. So it's you know deno
install. So the den website says,
"Hi, hi Zuma idiot. Just just copy and
paste and run in your shell." Okay.
Okay, no problem. Paste. Copy and paste.
Run it.
Gonna up my computer. [laughter]
Okay, it's running.
So, let's see the comment. Let me answer
the comment and be it. Okay. So, it's
like, oh the Deno is, you know,
how many megabyte, how many gigabyte am
I going to swallow?
Actually, I trust Deno. Okay, I mean,
Deno is far better than the MPM and nojs
scums. Okay, the MPM is created by a
scumbag. His name is uh Isaac something.
Okay, let me tell you guys. I said this
before,
but don't take my word for it, okay?
Because I don't really know that guy too
much. But I've seen in the past, you
know, five or 10 years,
you know, now and then, you know, the
the behavior of that guy Isaac, the guy
who created the MPM that up the
the NodeJS. Okay, Node.js. It was
created by the Ryan DA guy, a great guy.
kind of almost a genius like you know a
great capable guy. He created Node.js
that revolutionized the JavaScript
landscape. Okay. The entire community
meaning effectively
tens of millions of how industry works
with JavaScript. Okay. No.JS was created
about 15 years ago 2009 or so by Ryan
Dah. Okay. Then
he gave it basically he gave it to the
Isaac guy the guy who created MPM and
they it up. Okay. The that's this
is my opinion only. Okay. Just in case
they cannot sue me. This is my opinion
only. Okay. And also
a disclaimer. I don't actually know the
Isaac guy too much. Okay. I don't really
know the details, but I got the
impression he's not he's pretty nasty.
Okay, pretty nasty guy.
But anyway, then Ryan about five years
ago, you know, after 10 years, he he
created nojs. He realized there's some
mistakes and uh you know, because and
npm is one of the giant mistake. So he
tried to so he created uh demo
you know and you know starting fresh
demo entire new JavaScript and
Typescript
runtime and compiler. Okay. So I like
Deno very much. So for so my tip for you
guys doing JavaScript is that you should
switch to Deno. Okay. And never use mpm
especially and and especially npm don't
use nodejs and never use mpm okay there
are many alternative to npm you can use
yang or you can use today this uh I
learned there's a vite
upcoming new um you know javascript is
very um very interesting you know lots
of issue going going on javascript very
lousy language but uh recently I've been
you know you know I I've been trying to
I've been trying to uh understand all
this going on so there's a new thing
called vit or vite okay so so I'm
revisiting the JavaScript in the past 15
years the history of JavaScript you know
because I don't know actually so learn
so JavaScript modern JavaScript
explained for dinosaurs this is a great
article written 10 years ago in 2017 by
by this Chinese guy uh by this Chinese
guy uh Peter Jan. Okay, ve great
article. So if you are confused by about
react view you know the the angular like
what what why do you need this for you
know read this article and this is 10
years old. Okay. So anyway, so
JavaScript then you start you know you
begin you you you have NodeJS like 15
years ago. Then you you have B package
manager you have npm packaging manager
the scum. So I was saying the guy who
created npm is a major scumbag not a
good human. Okay, that's what I'm
saying. And uh tentatively too because I
don't actually know that guy too much
but I think you know I think so. Then
you you have young which is alternative
to npm.
Okay. So you got lots of JavaScript
landscape. You have browser back then.
So lots of this has been replaced. Okay.
Bossifi is kind of gone uh because you
know lots of reasons. Webpack is still
kind of going is basically gun too.
Okay, dead. Uh JavaScript user interface
framework React is still kicking. Uh
Babel is still kind of kicking. Okay,
and but I recommend just use Deno. Okay,
Deno, you don't even need uh Babel.
Okay, Vite is something I knew I learned
new. Vite is still become becoming very
popular. So v is like or vit is like the
new thing okay in in JavaScript land and
then you got the progressive Jav
JavaScript framework view okay that's
view uh then swelt also is kind of new
being been around for five years and
this S swc is new okay that's totally
new speedy web compiler that's
[laughter] that's another new thing in
Java so JavaScript land changes okay a
So anyway today we are we try to um
do demo to to do bundle and minify using
deeno but we realized our code my deeno
version is few years old they removed
the feature so
I tried to uh install deno so looks like
we installed it success successfully so
let's see uh where is my demo now
demo version
291. Wait, did we uh where is the new
version? Deno, did we uh
Oh, so you see we updated. So before was
2.31
successful. Okay, so now actually I can
run minify but I gotta go. I gotta
go. And now so let me read the comments
and that's it for today.
Uh god annoying this annoying popup you
cannot click. Uh hope you are still
here. Hi show.
Hi I'm new to your channel. I appreciate
all the work you have done for Emacs. I
wanted to know if there's a consolidated
list of all the Emacs packages that you
are open to selling. Uh yes that's
called Emacs. Okay. So, let me just show
you. Are you still here? It's like
[laughter]
you posted that like half an hour ago or
something, I think. So, uh, so you go to
Kasar Emacs, kasali.info, your
kasali.info, my website. Then you go to
Emacs, okay? Emacs blog. You can start
there or directly, you know, you can go
to my Emacs tutorial. Emacs, okay, so my
Emacs tutorial. Then you are uh
wondering about so uh about kasar the
packages. So kar emac packages. Okay. So
all these there so you got you know I
would say about five of them is very
robust. So look up you know I use all
the time. Uh find replace I use every
day better than all the
other methods you can do to find replace
in Emacs. Emacs has it built in of
course uh act well actually you need
Unix script you know that's a major flaw
with Emacs you need Unix script so on
windows if if you don't install Unix
script emacs cannot do find replace or
find or of all files in a directory but
my package can because it does not rely
on Unix script it's just pure eac
emac should do that but they don't you
know because they uh like basically
idiotic. Okay. Like like one of the most
important thing for text editor is to to
find replace for all files in a
directory. Essential for a text editor
especially if you think you know if you
think yourself is like a powerful text
editor but emac you can't do that. You
can't. No, we can. Well, you need to
install you the Unix. Unix grab
idiotic. And they if you know and you
have to install Unix fine to restore
directories. idiot.
Why? But Emacs list can do it of course
trivially but they don't you know
because well you you have to rely on the
uni. GNU is not Unix but you need Unix
or you need the GNU you know GNU
[laughter]
the GNU operating system called herd
which was a vaporware for 40 years you
still don't have it idiots
anyway so my package find
allows you to find gra or find and
replace for all files in your
directories like set Unix set without
any Unix utility Okay, I use it every
day and lookup I use every day. So uh
and um anyway about five or 10 actually
many of them especially HTML mode Java
JavaScript mode eag this mode these are
power
house host okay and CSS mode which are
also uh very good um so anyway but some
of them are like not really uh there yet
okay for example I have a Python mod do
I even this list here like F mo mode
F mode does nothing basically. Well, I
just began
uh and there's also Python mode which
doesn't really do anything. Anyway, a
lot of at least 10 of them is very
powerful after five years of work at
least. Okay, actually most of them is
more than 10 years of work. Okay, so if
you want everything if you you know so
that's Kasar Emacs. So you pay me. So
how much I ask for? 10 110. Okay.
Usually you don't. Okay. So I mean if
you are really interested if you know
consider it as a donation, you know, you
really enjoy my talk show, you enjoy the
way I work, my Emacs, you know, pay
$110, you get the whole thing. Okay? I
send you the whole thing.
It's all self-documented, you know. You
don't have to like there's no
extra tutorial for each one of them. All
you have to know is the the generic
Emacs way. How do you look up the
documentation the you know describe m
describe mode you know the generic Emacs
way. They are all selfdocumented because
I am obsessive about about
documentation. Every my function has a
documentation every one of them. Okay.
So they are self-documented. So you can,
you know, so some of them I have a
little tutorial like HTML mode because
this is the biggest one. This this is
like by now 5,000 lines of code
something. Okay, so you know you you
watch me use it every day in my live
stream. Okay, HTML mode. It can validate
entire directory. it you know you don't
see that tool anywhere because I I and I
code it live in liveream about three
years ago okay begin I began to code it
in live stream um so anyway so these are
the packages so you are wondering can
you get them all yeah you know you you
know pay me 110
uh you'll get it okay and actually I
haven't you know I'm so in a sad
situation I haven't read my email for
like two months. So even if you pay me,
I'm not seeing [clears throat] it. So
you can you know you can you can you can
get my attention on some discord on
Twitter especially on Twitter or discord
you know you can just tell me hey I paid
you you know check your email then then
I'll um
then then you know I'll see it because I
I don't I have not even read my emails
for for
okay so that I think I you know that
answer your question I tried searching
for them using the emoji in your website
but I think I did not find all of them
few streams ago you said that there's
specific package not listed there is so
you know so this is a list okay Emacs
uh it's basically up to you know that's
that's all that's the things you get
anyway yeah
so okay so I that's it bye
Why don't you use chocolate tea? Okay, I
answered that because I started to think
because when you use chocolate tea or
any of the package manager such as the
max on the Mac the um brew you know
typically you just blindly install it
like anytime anything you know you just
install install the you know you started
to lose
contact you know that that's the issue
with automation when you automate so
many things you started to lose contact
you started to not know or not care
about what's actually going on. If you
do things manually, you know, if you
always install things manually, you kind
of painful, but you you you you master
the process and you know exactly what's
where, why, you know, you have to
compile or you don't have to or what's
going on. Okay. When you rely on package
manager, yeah, sure. Sure. It's
convenient or even necessary especially
if you work in a job. It's necessary.
Okay, you cannot do without because
otherwise you're going to install 10
packages every day, you know, and you
need to update, you know, you if you do
it manually, you you know, you cannot
you but
there's a thing you became reliant you
have to trust whatever you like install
something you know it like typically
when you install like npm when you
install a package it installs 10
dependencies
Each one install 10 dependencies.
So when you type a command, you know,
install just, you know, I need this,
install it, it install one
thousand other packages.
That's very common in npm. Okay?
Especially in npm. It you type a
command, install something, install
1,000 fs. You have no idea who the
wrote them. Some of them, especially
with npm javascript, some of them is
like one line. Check if this is even
number you know check you know t trim
stream string you know I want to remove
the white space of a string you need the
library for that so so when you install
something install 10,000 things
that actually happens frequently so
that's a problem so like typically when
you install chalk install something oh
by the way it has these 10 other
dependencies are you Sure. You know, of
course, you just press yes. So that's a
issue. So I don't want that. And and one
of the thing the Deno guy Ryan Dah is a
great guy because specifically when he
designed Deno, he he he noticed like me.
Okay, I you know we don't want that you
install something, you install 10,000
other things. Okay, just one thing. Deno
is just one single executable.
Deno format, Deno whatever. But whatever
it can do is just one single executable.
Okay. So that's one you know that's from
Ryan D. I highly respect recommend that.
Can I uh pay via Patreon by subscribing
for for a specific amount as that works
better for international payment.
I would prefer PayPal because one shot.
You can do Patreon if you want.
But are you going to do like $100 one
month then stop next month? Because
Patreon is like, you know, it's the
periodic every month. You can't, you
know, so if you want to pay me 110,
then you have to wait for Patreon to to,
you know, after a month, then you have
to stop it. So it's like less less
convenient, I think. So, I would say
PayPal. If you do PayPal on me, then on
Twitter or Discord, just just tell me
you did, okay? Then I'll send you the
package. Okay? Bye, guys. I got I really
gotta go.